Will!
월!
- Why is this happening? - [don't know.
-무슨일이에요? - 모르겠소
You look beautiful.
아름답군
It's bad luck for the groom to see the bride before the wedding.
신부를 미리 보면 불길하대요
Make way! Let me through! How dare you!
비켜라, 비켜! 무례한 놈!
Stand your men down at once. Do you hear me?
무기를 치워! 안 들리나?
Governor Weatherby Swann, it's been too long.
스완 총독, 오랜만이요
- Cutler Beckett? - It's Lord now, actually.
-커틀러 베켓? -이젠베켓경이요
Lord or not, you have no reason and no authority to arrest this man.
경이고뭐고, 년 이 사람을 체포할권한이 없어
In fact. ldo. Mr. Mercer? a
권한이 있소, 가져와!
The warrant for the arrest of one William Turner.
월 터너의 체포영장이요
- This warrant is for Elizabeth Swann. - Is it? That's annoying. My mistake.
-엘리자베스영장이잖아? - 그래요?실수했소
- Arrest her. - On what charges?
-여자도 체포해 - 무슨 혐의로?
Aha. Here's the one for William Turner.
월 터너 영장이 여갔군
And I have another one for a Mr. James Norrington.
제임스 노링턴의 영장도 있소
- Is he present? - What are the charges?
-여기 있소? -죄목이뭐죠?
Commodore Norrington resigned his commission some months ago.
노링턴 제독은 몇 달 전에 사임했네
That wasn't the answer to the question I asked.
내 질문에나 답하시오
Lord Beckett. In the category of questions not answered...
베켓 경, 우린 대답할 의무 없소
We are under the jurisdiction of the king's governor of Port Royal
우린 총독의 통치권 하에 있어요
and you will tell us what we are charged with.
최목이 뭔지 말해줘요
The charge is "conspiring to set free
내가 읽지 '대영제국에 대한 반역죄로'
"a man convicted of crimes against the Crown and Empire
'사형선고 받은 자의'
"and condemned to death. a for which the...”
'탈출을 도운 죄, 그 죄과로.
For which the punishment, regrettably, is also death.
그 죄과로 함께 사형에 처함
Perhaps you remember a certain pirate named Jack Sparrow.
잭 스패로우란 해적 기억나지?
Captain.
선장이에요!
Captain Jack Sparrow.
잭스패로우선장
Yes, [ thought you might.
그래, 기억하는군
Fifteen men on a dead man’s chest
요하 을 <소증0 군호
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum
요호 요호, 롬주 한승 447
Drink and the devil had done for the rest
육 예도. 2 슬촛차0오
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of rum
요호 요호, 롬주 한승 447
Prisoners. come on! a
빨리들 움직여!
Sorry, mate.
미안해, 진구
Mind if we make a little side trip?
자네 다리 좀 빌릴게
I didn't think so.
고맘네
- Not quite according to plan. - Complications arose, ensued,
-어떻게된겁니까? -골아픈일이있었는데
were overcome.
해결됐어
You got what you went in for, then?
목적은 있나요?
Captain, I think the crew, meaning me as well,
우린 뭔가 반짝이는 걸.…
were expecting something a bit more shiny,
가져오실 걸로 기대했어요
with the Isla de Muerta going pear-shaped, reclaimed by the sea with the treasure.
저주 받은 섬과 보물은 바다에 가라앉았고.…
And the Royal Navy chasing us around the Atlantic.
해군은 우릴 쫓고 있소
- And the hurricane. - Aye.
-허리케인도 봅니다 -맞아
Allin all, it seems some time a since we did a speck of honest pirating.
무엇보다, 해적질 해본 지가 너무 까마득해요!
- Shiny. - Aye. shiny.
- 반짝이는 거? - 네, 반짝이는 거!
Is that how you're all feeling?
다들 날 못 믿나?
That perhaps dear old Jack is not serving your best interests as captain?
너희가 원하는 걸 못해줄것 같아?
Walk the plank.
바다에 빠뜨려!
- What did the bird say? - Do not blame the bird.
-새가뭐랬나? -새트집 잡지 말고
Show us what is on that piece of cloth there.
천에쓴거나보여줘요
- You know that don't do no good. - It does me.
-싸도안죽어요 -속은 후련해
- It's a key. - No. Much more better.
-열쇠잖아 -아니, 훨씬 좋은 거야
Itis a drawing of a key.
열쇠를 그린 그림이지
Gentlemen, a
여러분
what do keys do?
열쇠의 역할이 뭔가?
Keys
열쇠는.…
unlock things?
잠긴 걸 열죠
And whatever this key unlocks, inside there's something valuable.
잠겨있는 것 안엔 귀중한 게 들어있죠
So we're setting out to find whatever this key unlocks.
이제 그걸 찾으러 갈 거군요?
No.
아니!
If we con't have the key, we can't open whatever we don't have that it unlocks.
열쇠가없으면 잠긴 걸 못 열지
So what purpose would be served in finding whatever need be unlocked,
잠긴 걸 여는 열쇠가 없으면
which we don't have. without first a having found the key what unlocks it?
잠긴 걸 찾아 봤자 말짱 도루묵이야
So we're going after this key.
그럼 열쇠를 찾아야겠군요!
You're not making any sense at all.
말귀를 못 알아듣네
Any more questions?
또 질문 있나?
So do we have a heading?
그럼.… 항로는 어디죠?
A heading.
항로!
Set sail ina
우리가갈방향은.…
general
그러니까.…
that-way direction.
저 방향이다!
Captain?
선장?
Come on, snap to and make sail. You know how this works. Go on.
이나 올려! 장사 한두 번 해?비켜!
Have you noticed lately
요즘 들어 선장이
the captain seems to be acting a bit strange... er?
이상하다는 거 못 느껴요? 더욱?
Setting sail without knowing his own heading.
항로도 없이 가다니
Something's got Jack vexed, and mark my words,
뭔가 일이 일어난거야
what bodes ill for Jack Sparrow bodes ill for us all.
선장의 불행은 곧 우리 모두의 불행이야
Lord Beckett. a the prisoner as ordered, sir.
최인을 호송해 왔습니다
Those won't be necessary.
족쇄는 필요 없어
The East India Trading Company has need of your services.
동인도 무역회사가 널 필요로 한다
We wish for you to act as our agent
우리 양쪽의 친구인
in a business transaction with our mutual friend Captain Sparrow.
잭과의 사이에서 점자 노릇 좀해야겠어
More acquaintance. How do you know him?
친구라뇨? 그를 아시오?
We've had dealings in the past.
협상을 한적 있지
And we've each left our mark on the other.
서로의 몸에 표적을 남겼어
What mark did he leave on you?
그에게 어떤 표적을 남겼죠?
By your efforts, Jack Sparrow was set free.
네 도움으로 놈은 달아났다
I would like you to go to him
가서 놈이 갖고 있는
and recover a certain property in his possession.
어떤 물건을 찾아와
Recover. At the point of a sword?
찾아오라?무력으로?
Bargain.
협상해
Letters of marque.
나포 허가증이야
You will offer what amounts to a full pardon.
사면시켜준다고 해
Jack will be free. a a privateer in the employ of England.
민간 무장선 선장으로 임명하겠다고
Somehow I doubt Jack will consider employment the same as being free.
잭이 과연 그걸 자유로 여길까요?
Freedom.
자유?
Jack Sparrow is a dying breed.
해적의 시대는 갔다
The world is shrinking,
전 세계의 바다는
the blank edges of the map filled in.
강대국에 점령됐어
Jack must find his place in the New World or perish.
적응 못하면 죽음뿐이지
Not unlike you, Mr. Turner.
너처럼 말야, 월 터너
You and your fiancée face the hangman's noose.
년 약혼녀와 처형될 거야
- So you get Jack and the Black Pearl. - The Black Pearl?
-블랙펄을 차지하시게? - 블랙펄?
- The property you want that he possesses. - A ship? Hardly.
- 그걸 원하잖소 -배는 관심 없어
The item in question is considerably smaller and far more valuable. a
그 물건은 훨씬 작고 귀중한 거야
something Sparrow keeps on his person at all times.
잭이 늘 갖고 다니는 거지
A compass?
나침반!
You know it.
본적이 있군
Bring back that compass or there's no deal.
사형을 면하려면 나침반을 찾아와
Why is the rum always gone?
왜 렴주는 늘 없는 거야?
That's why.
아, 내가 마셨지!
As you were, gents.
계속들폭쉬어
Time's run out. Jack. a
시간이 됐네, 잭
Bootstrap.
부스트랩?
Bill Turner.
빌 터너?
You look good, Jack.
신수간하군
Is this a dream?
이거 꿈이죠?
No.
아니
I thought not. If it were, there'd be rum. a
하긴 꿈이면 술이 있겠지
You got the Pear! back, I see.
블랙펄 선장이 됐군
l had some help retrieving the Peari, by the way.
배를 되찾는 걸 누가 도와줬소
Your son.
당신 아들!
William?
월?
He ended up a pirate after all.
결국 해적이됐군
And to what clo I owe the pleasure of your carbuncle?
반갑잖게 엔일로 납셨소?
He sent me.
그가 보냈네
Davy Jones.
데비 존스
So it's you, then.
바로 당신이군
He shanghaied you into service. eh? a
그의 전령으로 선택된 게.…
I chose it.
내가 선택했어
I'm sorry for the part I played in the mutiny against you, Jack.
선상반란 때 자네 편을 들었던 게.…
I stood up for you.
너무 후회돼
Everything went wrong after that.
그뒤 모든 게 꼬였지
They strapped me to a cannon. l ended up on the bottom of the ocean,
난대포에 묶여 바다 밑에 처박혔어
the weight of the water crushing down on me.
바닷물에 짓눌려
Unable to move.
꼼짝할 수 없었지만
Unable to die. Jack. a
죽을 수도 없었네
And I thought that even the tiniest hope of escaping this fate, would take it.
그 운명을 벗을 수 있다면 뭐든 할 수 있었어
would trade anything for it.
그 어떤 짓도!
It's funny what a man will do to forestall his final judgment.
죄의 심판은 누구에게나 두렵죠
You made a deal with him too, Jack. a
그와거래했더군
He raised the Pear! from the depths for you.
그는 펼을 건져줬고
13 years, you've been her captain.
자덴 13년간 선장 노릇했어
- Technically... - Jack.
-정확히는.… - 재 ㄱ
You won't be able to talk yourself out of this.
모면할 생각 마
The terms what applied to me apply to you as well.
자네와 난 같은 운명이야
One soul bound to crew 100 years upon his ship.
100년간 그의 선원 노릇을 해야 돼
The Flying Dutchman already has a captain...
플라잉 더치맨엔 이미 선장이.…
Then it's the locker for you!
바다 밑에 같힐 텐가?
Jones's terrible leviathan will find you
존스의 괴물이 자네와 펄을
and drag the Pear! back to the depths and you along with it.
바다 밑바닥에 처넣을 거야!
Any idea when Jones might release said terrible beastie?
존스가언제 그 괴물을 풀 것 같소?
l already told you, Jack.
이미 말했잖나
Your time is up.
시간이 됐다고
It comes now. a
이제 곧괴물이
drawn with ravenous hunger to the man what bears the black spot.
심판의 표식을 가진 자를 공격해올 거야
On deck, all hands! a Make fast the bunt gasket!
출항한다! 나와서 둘 묶어!
On deck! Scurry!
다들 나와, 빨리!
Scurry! l want movement! Movement! I want movement!
동작 봐라, 빨리 움직여!
Lift the skin up! Keep your loof! Haul those sheets!
시간 없다, 외곽 늦 올려! 뱃머리 돌리고 을 펴!
Run them! Run! Keep running! Run as if the devil himself and itself is upon us!
잼싸게 움직여! 가랑이에서 방울소리 나게!
- Do we have a heading? - Run! Land.
-항로는요? -육지!
- Which port? - l didn't say “port,” I said "land." Any land.
- 어느 항구요? -그냥 육지, 아무데나!
- Jack's hat! Bring her about! - No. no! a
-선장모자떨어졌다,배돌려! -아냐
Leave it!
냄 뒤!
Run.
전력 항진해
Back to your stations, the lot of you!
위치로 가, 모두!
dack?
선장?
For the love of mother and child. Jack. oe what's coming after us?
무슨 일입니까? 누가 쫓아와요?
Nothing.
아냐
- Here, now, you can't be here. - [ think you'll find he can.
- 여긴 출입금지요! -내가허락했어
Mr. Swann!
스완 씨!
Governor Swann. still. a
아직 총독이야
Do you think I wear this wig to keep my head warm?
추워서 가발 쓴 줄 아나?
Jack's compass? What coes Beckett want with that?
잭의 나침반? 베켓이 그걸 왜요?
Does it matter? I'm to find Jack and convince him to return to Port Royal.
문제는 잭을 찾아 데려오는 거요
In exchange, the charges against us will be dropped.
그럼 우린 사면될 거요
No. We must find our own avenue to secure your freedom.
다른 방법을 찾아야 돼 웹지 못미더워
Is that a lack of faith in Jack or in me?
누가요? 잭이요, 저요?
That you would risk your life to save Sparrow
자덴 목숨 걸고 잭을 구했지만
does not mean he would do the same for anyone else.
잭도 과연 그럴까?
Now, where is that dog with the keys?
열쇠 가진 개 어디 있어?
I have faith in you.
전 당신을 믿어요
Both of you.
잭도요
Where will you find him?
어디서 그를 찾죠?
Tortuga. I'll start there and I won't stop searching till I find him.
토투가부터 가봐야지 꼭 그를 데려와서
And then I intend to return here to marry you.
당신과결혼할거요
- Properly? - Eagerly, if you'll still have me.
-식도 치르고요? - 당신만 안 변한다면
If it weren't for these bars. a I'd have you already.
창살이 원망스럽네요
- I'll wait for you. - Keep a weather eye on the horizon.
-기다릴게요 -늘 수평선을 지켜봐요
Captain Jack Sparrow?
잭 스패로우 선장?
Owes me four doubloons. Heard he was dead.
나한테 4냥 빚졌소 저 세상 사람이 됐다던데?
Singapore. That's what I heard. Drunk. with a smile on his face. a
싱가폴로 갔대요 술에 절어서!
Sure as the tide. Jack Sparrow turn up in Singapore.
확실해요 잭은 분명 싱가폴로 갔소
Jack Sparrow?
잭 스패로우?
l haven't seen him in a month.
그 인간못봤어요
When you find him, will you give him a message?
만나면 대신 전해쥐요
Can't say about Jack Sparrow,
잭에 대해선 말 못해요
but there’s an island just south of the straits
남쪽에 섬이 있긴 하지
where I trade spice for
내 물물 거래처
delicious long pork.
거기 사람 고기가 별미야
Cannot say about Jack, but you'll find a ship there.
잭 얘긴 할 수 없지만 그섬에배가있소
A ship with black sails.
검은 릎을 단 배
My brother will take you ashore.
내 동생이 안내할 거요
- What's wrong? The beach is there. - C'est trop dangereux.
왜 그래?다 와 가잖아
- What? - C'est trop dangereux. je vous l'avais dit.
뭐?
Bon voyage. monsieur.
즐.2요
Jack!
잭!
Jack Sparrow!
잭 스패로우!
Marty!
마티!
Cotton!
코튼!
Anybody?
아무도 없나?
A familiar face.
낮이 익군
Don't eat me.
날 잡아먹지 마
- I'm not going to eat you. - Don't eat me.
- 안 잡아먹어 - 잡아먹지 마
No. Don't eat me.
안 돼, 잡아먹지 마!
Gibbs.
기스 버ㅡ
Come on! Let's go!
덤내, 모두 덤벼!
Come on! Who wants it?
덤비라고, 어서!
I can do this all day!
안덤비고윗들해?
dack?
잭?
Jack Sparrow!
잭 스패로우!
I can honestly say I'm glad to see you.
이럴 땐 당신도 정말 반갑군요
Jack, it's me. a
잭, 나예요
Will Turner.
월 터너!
Tell them to let me down!
내려놓으라고 해요!
Jack, the compass. That's alll need.
잭, 나침반이 필요해요
Elizabeth is in danger. We were arrested for helping you.
엘리자베스가위험해요 당신 때문에 체포됐어요
She faces the gallows!
곧사형될 거예요!
Savvy?
오케이?
Save me.
날 구해줘
Jack, what did you tell them?
저들에게 뭐랬어요?
No!
안돼!
What about Elizabeth?
엘리자베스는 어떻게 해?
Jack!
잭!
That's a good girl. Come a little closer.
예쁜 아가씨, 이리 와봐
- We don't bite. - Go on. We won't bite you.
- 안 잡아먹어 - 가까이 와봐
Come quickly.
빨리 나와
- Tell me what's happening. - Our name still has some standing.
-어쩌시게요? -나 아직 힘 있어
I've arranged passage to England. The captain is a friend of mine.
영국행배선장을매수했다
No! Will's gone to find Jack!
안돼요! 월이 잭을 찾는 대요
We cannot count on William Turner.
그 친구 못 믿어
- Come! - He's better than you give him credit for.
-가자! -월을 과소평가 마세요
This is no time for innocence. Beckett has offered one pardon only -
듣기 싫다 베켓이 사면을 약속한 건
one, and that is promised to Jack Sparrow.
잭 스패로우 뿐이야
Even if Will succeeds. a
월이 성공해도
do not ask me to endure the sight of my daughter walking to the gallows. Do not.
년 교수형에 처해져 날더러 딸 죽는 걸 보란 거냐?
Perhaps I can ensure a fair trial for Will if he returns.
월이 돌아오면 공정한 재판을 약속하마
- A fair trial for Will ends in a hanging. - Then there is nothing left for you here.
- 공정해봤자교수형이죠 -그럼더여기있을이유없지
Wait inside.
안에서 기다려
Captain?
선장?
Captain.
선장!
Evening, Governor.
총독 나으리
Shame, that. a
유감이요
He was carrying this.
이걸 갖고 있었소
It's a letter to the king.
국왕께 전하는 편지
- It's from you. - No...
-당신이썼더군 -이런.…
Elizabeth.
엘리자베스!
What are you doing?
무슨 짓이냐?
- Where is she? - Who?
-어디 있소? -누구?
No doubt you've discovered that loyalty is no longer the currency of the realm,
당신 아버지처럼 왕실에 충성하는 거
as your father believes.
여기선 안먹혀
Then what is?
그럼 뭐가 먹히죠?
I'm afraid currency is the currency of the realm.
이제 여기선 돈이 곧법이지
l expect, then, we can come to some sort of understanding.
그럼 나와 얘기가 통하시겠네
- I'm here to negotiate. - I'm listening.
-협상하러왔어요 -말해봐
I'm listening intently.
귀가 쯤굿세워지는군
These letters of marque are signed by the king.
국왕의 나포허가증이야
Yes, and they're not valid until they bear my signature and my seal.
내셔명과봉인이없인무효야
Or else I would not still be here.
그래서 못 떠났어
You sent Will to get you the compass owned by Jack Sparrow.
나침반 찾으러 월을 보냈지?
- It will do you no good. - Do explain.
-바보짓한거야 -어째서?
l have been to the Isla de Muerta. l have seen the treasure myself.
난죽음의 섬에 가봤어 보물도 봤지
- There is something you need to know. -lsee.
-당신이 모르는 게 있어 -혹시.…
You think the compass leads only to the Isla de Muerta
나침반은 죽음의 섬 쪽만 가리킨다는 거?
and so you hope to save me from an evil fate.
내가 죽을까봐 걱정되시나?
But you mustn't worry.
걱정하지마
I care not for cursed Aztec gold.
저주 받은 아즈텍의
My desires are not so provincial.
황금 따위엔 관심 없어
There's more than one chest of value in these waters.
바다엔 보물상자가 지천이야
So perhaps you may wish to enhance your offer.
협상조건을좀높여보시지?
Consider into your calculations that you robbed me of my wedding night.
당신이 내 결혼식 망친 걸 잊지 마
So I did.
안잊었어
A marriage interrupted
내가 망친 걸까.…
or fate intervenes?
네 운명이 짓굿은 걸까?
You're making great efforts to ensure Jack Sparrow's freedom.
잭의 자유를 위해 꽤 애쓰는군
- These aren't going to Jack. - Really?
-잭에게 줄거아냐 - 그래?
To ensure Mr. Turner's freedom. then, ee
월을 위해서다?
I'll still want that compass.
난 나침반이 필요해
Consider that in your calculations.
그걸 부디 잊지 말라고
I say it was Divine Providence what escaped us from jail.
우리가 탈출한건 주님의 섭리야
And I say it was me being clever.
웃기네! 내가 똑똑해서야
Ain't that right, poochie?
안 그러냐, 푸치?
Well, how'd you know it weren't Divine Providence what inspired you to be clever?
네가 똑똑한 것도 주님의 섭리 야
Anyways, l ain't stealing no ship.
난그배안흠칠래
It ain't stealing. It's salvaging. And since when did you care?
흠치는 게 아니고 인양이야 언제부터 그런 거 따졌냐?
Since we're not immortal no more. We gotta take care of our immortal souls.
우리 영혼은 불멸이야 심판을 받게 돼있어!
- You know you can't read. - It's the Bible. You get credit for trying.
-너 글은 아냐? -읽는 척만 해도 구원 받아
Pretending to read the Bible's a lie. That's a mark against...
성경을 읽는 척만 하는 건 사기야! 위에서 열 받는다고!
Look.
봐!
There it is.
저기 있다
What's got into him?
저 녀석 왜 저래?
Must have seen a catfish.
켓피시를 봤나?
Stupid mongrel!
멍청한 똥개!
Come on!
빨리 와!
- It's ours for the taking. - Tide’s coming in. That should help.
-배가거저생겼네! -밀물이라 골기도 쉬워
And salvaging is saving, in a manner of speaking.
이거 분명히 인양이지?
There's the truth of it!
배를 구원하는 거야!
Suppose we better save it as Soon as we can. a
최대한 신속히 구원해야겠다
what with our souls in such a vulnerable state and all.
이 배의 영혼은 연약하니까
Amen to that.
그 말에 아멘!
Thank you.
고맘다
Why would he do this to us? If Jack is the chief...
잭이 추장인데 왜 우릴 가뒷지?
Aye. the Pelegostos made Jack their chief. a
저들이 추장 삼은 거요
but he only remains chief as long as he acts like a chief.
추장처럼 굴어야무사해요
So he had no choice. He's a captive as much as the rest of us.
잭도 우리처럼 포로군
Worse, as it turns out. See, the Pelegostos believe that Jack is a god in human form,
더못한신세죠 잭을 신으로 여겨요
and they intend to do him the honor of releasing him from his fleshy prison.
육신의 못을 벗겨 완전하게 만든대요
They'll roast him and eat him.
구워서 잡아먹을 거요
Where's the rest of the crew?
동료들은 어디 있나?
These cages we're in weren't built till after we got here.
이 우리가 바로 동료들뻐로 만든 거요
The feast is about to begin.
곧축제가시작돼요
Jack's life will end
북소리가멈추면
when the drums stop.
잭은 죽을 거요
Well, we can't just sit here and wait, then. can we? a
그럼 이럴 때가 아니군
No, no. Oi! No, no. re
아냐, 잠깐만!
More wood. Big fire. Big fire.
감더 가져와! 더 활활 지펴!
lam Chief. Want big fire.
난 추장이야, 활활 지펴!
Come on.
어서!
Tout de suite. Come on. More wood.
떨감 가져와, 뛰어가!
Bugger.
엄마야
A little seasoning, eh?
양념 쳐야지
Well done.
골고루 구원
Put your legs through. Start to climb!
발을 깊고 기어올라가!
Come on. men! a It ll take all of us to crew the Black Pearl!
힘내! 배 몰려면 자네들 다 필요해
Actually, you wouldn't need everyone.
솔직히 다필요하진 않죠
About six would do.
여섯이면 돼요
Oh, dear. a
이런 젠장
- Hurry! - Come on!
-서둘러! - 올라가!
Come on! Is that all you got?
빨리 올라가, 궁이들아!
Wait. Stop.
정지!
- What are they doing? - Stop.
-뭐 하는 거야? -멈춰!
Snake!
뱀이다!
Move!
올라가!
Well, go on, go get them.
뭐해?가서 잡아와
No, no. Oi! No, no! re
이봐, 잠깐!
Not good.
일 났네
Cut it loose! Find a rock!
줄을 잘라! 돌을 찾아봐!
Roll the cage!
우리를 굴려!
Come on!
빨리!
- Lift the cage! Hurry! - Come on, lads. Lift it like a lady's skirt.
-우리를 들어! -여자치마들추듯높이 들어!
Run!
뛰어!
This way, lads!
이쪽으로!
Take cover!
몸을 숨겨!
Stop it!
동작 그만!
Bugger.
젠장
Haul loose the mooring line!
줄을 풀어, 라게티!
The mooring line!
둘을 풀라고!
Thief! Little hairy thief! Give it back!
이 털북숭이 도둑아, 내나!
- Don't bite it! - Haul loose the mooring line!
-깨물지 마! -줄풀라니까!
He's got me eye. He won't give it back.
저게 내 눈알 흠쳐갔어!
- How'd you get it back last time? - Excellent! Our work's half done.
- 눈깔 간수 좀 잘해! -우리할일을 다해났네
We done it for you, knowing you'd be coming back.
올 줄 알고 해났지
- Make ready to sail, boys! - What about Jack?
- 올릴 준비해! -잭은?
l won't leave without him.
두고 갈순 없어!
- Time to go. - Cast off those lines!
-빨리 가자 -어서줄풀어!
Make ready to cast off!
출항 준비해!
Good doggy.
작하지
Alas, my children, this is the day you shall always remember as the day you almost...
식인종들이여, 오늘을 기억하라 잭 스패로우를.…
Captain Jack Sparrow.
구워 먹을 뻔한 날로.…
Let's get away from this island and head out to open sea.
멀리 나갑시다 심해 가운데로!
Yes to the first. Yes to the second. but a only insofar as we keep to the shallows.
심해 가운데로 가되 근해를 벗어나진 마
That seems a bit contradictory, Captain.
그건 앞뒤가 안 맞죠
I have faith in your reconciliatory navigational skills.
난 앞뒤 맞는 말이면 할려
Now, where is that monkey? I want to shoot something.
원숭이 있나? 한방 싸쥐야겠어
Jack. Elizabeth is in danger.
엘리자베스가위험해요
Have you considered just locking her up somewhere?
자꾸 사고 치면 방에 가뒤뒤
She is locked up, bound to hang for helping you.
당신을 돕다가 사형수가 됐어요!
There comes a time when one must take responsibility for one’s mistakes.
실수의 대가는 누구나 치르는 법이야
I need that compass of yours, Jack.
그 나침반이 필요해요
I must trace it for her freedom.
엘리자베스와 교환해야돼요
- Mr. Gibbs. - Captain.
-김스! -네!
We have a need to travel upriver.
강 상류로 가야겠다
By need, do you mean a trifling need?
왜요? 또 맘이 바뀌셨소?
Fleeting? As in, say, a passing fancy?
또 변덕이 끌어올라요?
No, a resolute and unyielding need.
아니, 이번엔 신중히 결정한 거야
What we need to do is make sail for Port Royal with all haste.
포트 로열로 당장 출발해야 돼!
William. a
월
I shall trade you the compass
나침반을 줄 테니
if you will help me
대신 내가
to find this.
이걸 찾게 도와줘
- You want me to find this? - No.
- 이걸 찾아달라고? -달라니!
You want you to find this,
모두 자넬 위해서야
because the finding of this finds you incapacitorially finding
이걸 찾아야지만 약혼녀인지 뭐시갱인지를 찾을
and’or locating in your discovering a way to save your dolly belle, ol’ what's-her-face.
방법을 찾을 수 있다 이 말씀이야
Savvy?
오케이?
This is going to save Elizabeth?
이게 엘리자베스를 구한다고요?
How much cdo you know about Davy Jones?
혹시 데비 존스에 대해 잘 아나?
Not much.
아뇨
Yeah, it's going to save Elizabeth.
그래, 이게 구할 수 있어
What's all this?
뭔가?
If you both fancy the dress, you'll just have to share and wear it one after the other.
드레스가 탐나면 번갈아 가며 돌려 써
It's not like that. sir. a This ship is haunted.
그게 아닙니다 배에 유령이 있어요
Is it, now? And you?
그래? 사실인가?
There's a female presence amongst us here, sir.
여자유령이 돌아다닙니다
All the men, they can feel it.
손에 만져져요
It's the ghost of a lady widowed before her marriage. I figure it,
약혼자를 바다에 잃은 여자가
searching for her husband, lost at sea.
약혼자를 찾아 떠돈대요
A virgin too, likely as not.
처녀유령일 겁니다
And that bodles ill by all accounts.
아주 불길해요
I say that we throw the dress overboard and we hope the spirit follows it.
드레스를 바다에 던지면 따라 뛰어내릴 겁니다
No! That will just anger the spirit, sir.
그럼 유령이 화냄니다
What we need to do is find out what the spirit needs, and then get it back to her.
유령이 원하는 걸 찾아 돌려줘야돼요!
Enough! Enough!
그만해!
You're a pair of superstitious goats and it's got the best of you.
바보 같이 그런 미신을 믿나?
Now, this appears to be no more as we have a stowaway on board.
배에 밀항자가 탄 거야
A young woman, by the look of it.
젊은 여자일 거다
I want you to search the ship and find her.
배를 살살이 뒤져
Oh, and she's probably naked.
아마 발가벗고 있을 거야
Why is Jack afraid of the open ocean?
잭이 왜 바다를 겁내지?
Well, if you believe such things,
데비 존스에겐
there's a beast does the bidding of Davy Jones -
무서운 괴물부하가있대요
a fearsome creature with giant tentacles that'll suction your face clean off
거대한 촉수로 얼굴을 빨아 마시고
and drag an entire ship down to the crushing darkness.
바닷속으로 배를 글고 들어간대
The kraken.
크라켄!
They say the stench of its breath is like...
입 냄새가죽음이라더군
Imagine, the last thing you know on God's green earth
안겪어보면 상상조차 못 한대
is the roar of the kraken and the reeking odor of a thousand rotting corpses.
크라켄의 끔찍한 포효소리와 시체 썩는 듯한 악취 를.
If you believe such things.
안 믿으면 말고
And the key will spare him that?
열쇠가있으면 안전해?
Well, that's the very question Jack wants answered.
잭도 그게 궁금해서
Bad enough even to go visit
이렇게 찾아가는 거요
her.
그 여자를 말요
Her?
그 여자?
Aye.
그래요
No worries. mates. a Tia Dalma and I go way back.
걱정들 마 티아 달마와난오랜친구야
Thick as thieves. Nigh inseparable, we are.
의리로 뭉친 사이지
Were. Have been.
사이였지, 한때는
Before.
옛날엔
- I'll watch your back. - It's me front I'm worried about.
-뒤는걱정마요 -앞이 걱정이야
- Mind the boat.
-보트잘지켜요 - 보트 잘지켜
Mind the boat.
보트 잘 지켜!
Jack Sparrow.
잭 스패로우
Tia Dalma.
티아 달마!
l always knew the wind was going to blow you back to me one day.
언젠간 꼭다시 찾아올 줄알았어
You...
네게선.…
You have a touch of
운명의 그림자가
destiny about you,
아른거리고 있어
William Turner.
월 터너
You know me?
날 아시오?
You want to know me.
지금부터 알면 되지
There'll be no knowing here. We've come for help and we're not leaving without it.
연애걸때가아냐 도움 받으러 왔어
- [ thought I knew you. - Not so well as I had hoped.
- 날 좋아했잖아 -네가시큰둥했지
- Come.
-이리와 - 와!
What service may I do you?
내가 뭘 해주길 원해?
- You know I demand payment. - [brought payment.
-보수는줄거지? -준비했어
Look.
봐!
An undead monkey.
죽지 않는 원숭이
Top that.
멋지지?
Don't! You've no idea how long it took us to catch that.
이런! 잡느라고 죽을 똥 는데!
The payment is fair.
보수는 충분하군
We're looking for this.
이걸 찾고 있소
And what it goes to.
이걸로 열 상자도
The compass you bartered from me, it cannot lead you to this?
내가 준 나침반으로 이걸 못 찾아?
Maybe. Why?
그럴걸?왜?
Jack Sparrow does not know what he wants.
네가 찾는 게 뭔지 정말 모르는 거야?
Or do you know,
아니면 그게 네 거란 걸
but are loath to claim it as your own?
숨기려고 쇼 하는 거야?
Your key go to a chest.
이건 어떤 상자의 열쇠야
And it is what lay inside the chest you seek, don't it?
그 상자에 든 걸 찾는 거지?
- What is inside? - Gold?
-뭐가 들었소? - 황금?
Jewels? Unclaimed properties of a valuable nature?
보석? 주인 없는 진귀한 보물?
Nothing bad, I hope?
나쁜 건 아니겠죠?
You know of Davy Jones,
데비 존스에 대해
yes?
알아?
A man of the sea.
바다의 사나이지
A great sailor,
훌륭한 뱃사람이었는데
until he run afoul of that which vex all men.
모든 남자의 영원한 적을 만났어
What vexes all men?
그 적이뭐요?
What indeed?
글써, 뭘까?
- The sea. - Sums.
- 바다? -덧셈!
The dichotomy of good and evil.
선악의 흑백논리?
A woman.
여자!
He fell in love.
사랑에 빠진 거야
No, no. no. no. a heard it was the sea he fell in love with.
그럴 리 없어 바다와 사랑에 빠졌다던데?
Same story, different versions, and all are true.
너전은 달라도 다 같은 얘기 야
See, it was a woman a
그 여잔 바다처럼
as changing and harsh
변덕이 심하고 거칠고
and untamable as the sea.
잔인하고 멋대로였어
Him never stopped loving her.
그는 그래도 사랑했지
But the pain it cause him was too much to live with
그 고통은 살기 싫을 만큼 켰지만
but not enough to cause him to die.
죽을 만큼 크진 않았어
What exactly did he put into the chest?
그가 상자에 넣은 게 정확히 뭐요?
Him heart.
자기 심장
Literally or figuratively?
진짜 심장 말이요?
He couldn't literally put his heart in a chest.
상자에 어떻게 진짜 심장을 넣냐?
Could he?
가능해요?
It was not worth feeling what small, fleeting joy life brings.
인생의 짧은 쾌락이 덧없게만느껴진 그는
And so
자기 심장을
him carve out him heart. a
칼로 도려내어
lock it away in a chest and hicle the chest from the world.
상자에 넣은 다음 세상으로부터 감춰났지
The key
그리고 열쇠는.…
he keep with him at all times.
그가 늘지니고있어
- You knew this. - [did not. I didn't know where the key was.
- 알고 있었지? - 아니, 전혀 몰랐어
But now we do. All that's left is to climb aboard the Flying Dutchman, grab the key,
플라잉 더치맨호에 있겠군 그배에서 열쇠를 흠쳐
you go back to Port Royal and save your bonnie lass, eh?
자덴 애인을 구하면 되겠네!
Let me see your hand.
손 이리 줘봐
The black spot!
검은 표식이다!
- The black spot! - Black spot!
-저주여, 물러가라! -물러가라!
My eyesight's as good as ever, just so you know.
내 앞에서 꼴값들 해라
I have just the thing. Now, where did I put it?
그걸 어디 뒷더라? 잘뒷는데.…
My little beauty, where are you?
내 보물단지, 어덤니?
Such a long time in such a mess.
너무 권이 처박아뒷나?
Davy Jones cannot make port.
데비 존스는 10년에 한번 밖에
Cannot step on land but once every ten years.
땅을 밝을 수 없어
Land is where you are safe, Jack Sparrow,
잭, 년 땅에선 안전해
and so you will carry land with you.
흙을 지니고 다녀
Dirt.
흙!
- This is a jar of dirt. - Yes.
- 흙을 담은 병이군 -그래
Is the jar of dirt going to help?
흙 담은 병이 도움이 될까?
If you don't want it, give it back.
도움 안될 것 같아? 그럼 줘!
- No. - Then it helps.
-아냐 - 그럼 도움되겠지
It seems we have a need to find the Flying Dutchman.
이제 플라잉 더치맨 호를 찾아야겠군
A touch of destiny.
운명이여 말해다오!
That's the Flying Dutchman?
저게 플라잉 더치맨인가?
- She doesn't look like much. - Neither do you.
-별거아니군 -자네도그래
Do not underestimate her.
저 배 우습게 보지 마
- Must have run afoul of the reef. - So, what's your plan, then?
- 암초에 걸렸나 봐요! -작전이뭔가?
l row over, search the ship until find your bloody key.
노저어가서 열쇠를 찾아와야죠
And if there are crewmen?
선원들이 있으면?
I cut down anyone in my path.
방해되면 다없앨 거요
l like it. Simple, easy to remember.
작전이 간단해서 기억하긴 첩군
Your chariot awaits you, Sire.
노 저을 줄은 알죠?
If you do happen to get captured, just say Jack Sparrow sent you to settle his debt.
혹시 잡히면 내 빚 갖으러 왔다고 해!
- It might save your life. - Bon voyage!
-그럼 안 죽일지도 몰라! -잘다녀오쇼!
Douse the lamps.
램프 불 꺼!
Sailor.
이봐요
- Hoisting the jib, Captain's orders. - Sailor!
- 높을 올려, 선장 명령이다! -이봐!
Hoisting the jib. Bring up with a round turn.
우현으로 급히 꺼어!
There's no use. You've run aground.
이 배 좌초했소
No.
아냐
Beneath us.
그가 밑에 있어
Foul breath.
냄새가 고약해
Down on your marrowbones and pray.
무릎 꿀고 기도나 하지 그래
Get back! Get back!
물러서! 물러서!
Five men still alive. The rest have moved on.
다섯 놈은 살아있고 나머진 죽었습니다
Do you fear death?
죽음이 두려운가?
Do you fear that dark abyss?
저 어눔의 심연이 두려운가?
All your deeds laid bare.
죽으면 모든 게 드러나
All your sins punished.
모든 죄를 심판 받지
I can offer you
벗어날 방법을
an escape.
말해줄까?
Don't listen to him!
그 말 듣지 마!
Do you not fear death?
년 죽음이 안 두렵나?
I'll take my chances, sir.
행한 대로 받겠죠
To the depths.
바다에 던져
Cruel blackguard!
잔인한 놈!
Life is cruel.
삶은 잔인한 거야
Why should the afterlife be any different?
죽음 후의 삶이라고 다를까?
l offer you a choice.
네게 선택권을 주겠다
Join my crew
내 선원이 되어
and postpone the judgment.
심판을 연기 받아
One hundred years before the mast.
100년만복역하면돼
Will ye serve?
그렇게 하겠나?
I will serve.
그러겠습니다
You are neither dead nor dying.
년 죽지도, 죽어가지도 않잖아
What is your purpose here?
여긴 왜 왔나?
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
잭의 빚을 갖으러 왔소
What is your purpose here?
윗 때문에 왔다고?
Jack Sparrow sent me to settle his debt.
잭 스패로우의 빚을 갔으러 왔소
Did he. now? a
널 대신 보냈다?
I'm sorely tempted to accept that offer.
그거 구미 당기는 조건이군
You have a debt to pay.
년 내게 빚이 있어
You've been captain of the Black Pear! for 13 years.
계약대로 13년간 블랙펄 선장 노릇 했잖아
That was our agreement.
그게 우리 계약이었어!
Technically l was only captain for two years, then I was mutinied upon.
2년 해먹고 폭동 나서 쫓겨났소
Then you were a poor captain, but a captain nonetheless.
쫓겨나도 명색은 선장이었어!
Have you not introduced yourself all these years
늘 남에게 네 자신을
as Captain Jack Sparrow?
잭 선장으로 소개했잖아!
You have my payment. One soul to serve on your ship.
절 데려왔으니까 빚 갔은 걸로 합시다
One soul is not equal to another.
널 한 명과 바꿀순없지
We've established my proposal is sound in principle. Now we're haggling over price.
조건엔 동의해요? 그럼 흥정만 남았군
Price?
흥정?
Just how many souls do you think my soul is worth?
내 영훈을 몇 명과 바꾸고 싶소?
One hundred souls.
100명의 영혼
Three days.
사흘 주지
You're a diamond. mate. Send me back a the boy. I'll get started right off.
약속은 꼭 지킬 테니 저 친군 돌려줘요
l keep the boy. A good-faith payment.
저 놈은 담보로 데리고 있겠다
That leaves you only 99 more to go.
99명만더데려와
Have you not met Will Turner?
월과 초면이오?
He's noble, heroic. a a terrific soprano.
싸움도 노래도 잘 해요
Worth at least four.
4명 분은 돼
Maybe three and a half.
적어도 3명 반
And did l happen to mention
연애 중이란 얘기도
he’s in love?
내가 했던가?
With a girl.
여자랑!
Due to be married.
곧결혼할거요
Betrothed.
약혼했거든
Dividing him from her and her from him would only be half as cruel
두 사람을 떼놓는 것보단
as actually allowing them to be joined in holy matrimony. Eh?
결혼하게 뇌두는 게 몇 배 가혹한 벌이요
Il keep the boy. 99 souls.
제리고 있겠다 99명 데려와
But I wonder, Sparrow,
그나저나 의문이군
can you live with this?
네 명예는 괜찮겠나?
Can you condemn an innocent man, a friend. a
최 없는 친구를 네 대신 바치고
to a lifetime of servitude in your name while you roam free?
년 자유를 얻는다면 비난 받을 텐데?
Yep. I'm good with it.
괜잖소, 상관없어
Shall we seal it in blood? I mean ink.
피의 맹세를 할까요? 참, 피가 없든가?
Three days.
사흘 주마
- Mr. Gibbs. - Aye.
-기스 버ㅡ -네
I feel sullied and unusual.
기분이 끈적끈적 엿 같아
And how do you intend to harvest these 99 souls in three days?
사흘 안에 어떻게 99명을 잡아오죠?
Fortunately, he was mum as to the condition in which these souls need be.
99명 상태에 대해선 조건을 안 붙였어
Tortuga.
토투가점!
It's an outrage. Port tariffs, berthing fees,
말도 안돼! 항구 이용료, 정박료.…
wharf handling and, heaven help us, pilotage.
부두 유지비, 관세까지 받다니!
Are we all to work for the East India Trading Company, then?
이건 동인도 회사의 횡포야!
I'm afraid, sir, Tortuga is the only free port left in these waters.
무관세 항은 토투가 뿐입니다
A pirate port is what you mean. Well, I'm sorry.
해적들의 섬?
An honest sailor is what lam. l make my living fair and I sleep well each night.
난 정직한 군인이야 법대로 일하고 맘 편히 자고 싶어
Sir!
대령님!
She wants you to do something.
원하는 게 있나 봅니다
She's trying to give a sign.
저건 계시가 틀림없어
Over there! Look for a sign!
저쪽이다 계시를 찾아봐!
Look, there! There it is! a
봐, 저기 있다!
- There's the sign! - That's seaweed.
-계시! -해초잖아
- Seaweed can be a sign. - Looks like entrails.
-해초도 계시가될 수 있어 -내장같군
- That would be a bad sign. - What's that over there?
- 불길한 징조야 -저건뭐지?
And what makes you think you're worthy to crew the Black Pear!?
정말 블랙펄에서 일할 수 있겠소?
I've never sailed a day in me life.
사실 뱃일은 처음이요
I figure I should get out, see the world while I'm still young.
그냥젊을 때세상구경하려고
You'll do. Make your mark. Next!
좋소, 서명해요 다음!
My wife ran off with my dog
마누라가개랑 도망쳐서
and I'm drunk for a month
한 달간 술만 퍼먹었소
and I don't give an ass rat's
이 놈의 팔자
if l live or die.
죽든 말든 상관없소
- Perfect. Next! - [Know what I want. [ Know what I want...
-완벽해, 다음! -괜찮아, 괜찮아.…
- Me have one arm and a bum leg. - It's the crow’s nest for you.
-난외팔에절름발이요 - 망루를 맡아요
- [Know what I want. - Next!
-방향을 일러줘 - 다음!
Ever since I was a little lad. a I've always wanted to sail the seas forever.
영원히 바다를 떠도는 게 내 평생 소원이었소
Sooner than you think. Sign the roster.
원대로 해주겠소, 서명해요
Thanks very much.
고맘소
- How we going? - Including those four, that gives us four.
-몇 명이야? -저네명합해서모두.…넷이요
And what's your story?
당신 사연은 뭐요?
My story.
난여태.…
It's exactly the same as your story, just one chapter behind.
자네들과 똑같은 행적을 밝아왔어
I chased a man across the seven seas.
어떤 놈을 찾아 바다를 누벼
The pursuit cost me my crew,
그 덕에 부하들과
soe my commission,
내 직위.…
and my life.
인생까지 잃었어
- Commodore? - No, not anymore. Weren't you listening?
-제독? - 이젠 아냐, 여태 뭘 들었나?
I nearly had you all off Tripoli.
네놈들 다체포할뻔했는데
I would have. a if not for the hurricane.
그 놈의 허리케인만 아니었으면!
Lord.
맘소사
You didn't try to sail through it?
허리케인을 못 피했소?
So, dol make your crew
합격인지 아닌지
or not?
그거나 말해
You haven't said where you're going.
목적지는 어딘가?
Somewhere nice?!
멋진 곳이겠지?
So, am I worthy to serve
나도 잭 스패로우 선장을
under Captain Jack Sparrow?
모실 자격이 있나?
Or should I just kill you now?
아니면 확 싸버릴까?
You're hired.
채용할게
Sorry. Old habits and all that.
미안해 습관은 안 고쳐져
- Easy, sailor! - That's our captain you're threatening.
-미쳤나? -감히 선장님을 싸?
- Time to go. - Aye!
-출발하자 -네!
Thanks, mate. a
고맘네
Carry on.
계속해
Come on. then! Who wants some? a
다덤내, 덤벼보라고!
Form an orderly line and I'll have you all, one by one.
줄서, 한 놈씩 보내줄 테니까!
Come on. who's first? a
누가 먼저야?
I just wanted the pleasure of doing that myself.
재밌어 길래 해봤어
James Norrington.
제임스 노링턴
What has the world done to you?
왜 이 꼴이 됐어요?
Heave!
힘껏 당겨!
- Heave!
-당겨! -힘껏!
Secure the mast tackle. Mr. Turner! a
마스트 로프를 묶어, 터너!
Set to it!
빨리 해!
- Step aside. - Hey! Mind yourself!
-비켜요! -너나비켜!
Let go, boy!
이거 !
No.
안돼!
Haul that weevil to his feet.
저 녀석을 불에 묶어!
Five lashes will remind you to stay on 'em!
실수한 대가로 채찍 다섯 대다!
- No! - Impeding me in my duties?
-안돼! -내가하는 일을 감히 방해해?
- You'll share the punishment. - I'll take it all.
-너도 맞아볼래? -내가 다맞겠소
Will you, now?
네가 맞겠다?
And what would prompt such an act of charity?
왜 갑자기 그런 자비심이 생겼나?
My son.
아들이요
He's my son.
내 아들
What fortuitous circumstance be this?
이거 일이 재밌게 됐군
Five lashes be owed. I believe it is. a
정한벌칙은 이행해야지
No. No, I won't!
싫어요, 난 못해요!
The cat's out of the bag, Mr. Turner.
저항해도 소용없어, 터너!
Your issue will feel its sting, be it by the bosun's hand or your own.
갑판장에게 맞든 네게 맞든 맞긴 맞아야 돼
No.
안돼
- Bosun! - No!
- 갑판장! -안돼요!
You had it easy, boy!
너 운 좋았다, 짜샤!
- Will. - [don't need your help.
-월! -내 일에 상관마요!
The bosun prides himself on cleaving flesh from bone, with every swing.
갑판장한테 맞으면 살점이 다떨어져나가!
So I'm to understand what you dic was an act of compassion?
날 생각해서 때렸단 건가요?
Yes.
그래
100 years before the mast, losing who you were, bit by bit,
100년간 바다에 같혀 자신을 점차 잃어가다.…
until you end up... end up like poor Wyvern here.
결국 이 가였은 위번처럼 될래?
Once you've sworn an oath to the Dutchman, there's no leaving it.
한 번맹세하면돌이킬수없어
Not until your debt is paid.
빚을 갖기 전엔
I've sworn no oath.
맹세 안했어요
You must get away.
어서 도망가
Not until I find this.
이걸 찾아야 돼요
The key.
열쇠요!
The dead man's chest.
망자의 함
What clo you know of this?
그걸 알아요?
Open the chest with the key, and stab the heart...
열쇠로 함을 열고 심장을 찔러
No, don't stab the heart. a
아냐, 심장은 찌르지 마
The Dutchman needs a living heart or there'll be no captain,
더치맨에게 심장이 없으면 선장도 없어
and if there's no captain, there's no one to have the key.
선장이 없으면 열쇠주인도 없지
So the captain has the key?
선장이 열쇠를 갖고 있소?
- Where is the key? - Hidden.
-열쇠어디있죠? -숨겨났어
- Where is the chest?
-함은 어디 있소?
Captain Sparrow!
스패로우 선장!
Come to join me crew, lad? Welcome aboard.
선원이 되게?환영하네
I'm here to find the man I love.
연인을 찾으러 왔어요
I'm deeply flattered, son, but my first and only love is the sea.
고맘네만 난 바다만을 사랑해
Meaning William Turner, Captain Sparrow.
월 터너 말이에요, 선장
Elizabeth.
엘리자베스?
Hicle the rum.
럼주 숨겨
These clothes do not flatter you. It should be a dress or nothing.
남장할 바엔 차라리 벗어요
- [happen to have no dress in my cabin. - Jack.
-빌려줄드레스도 없소 -잭!
I know Will came to find you. Where is he?
월 왔죠?어디 있어요?
Darling, l am truly unhappy to have to tell you this, but
이런 말하기 가슴 아프지만
through unfortunate circumstances that had nothing whatsoever to do with me,
나랑 상관없는 복잡한 사정 때
poor Will has been press-ganged into Davy Jones's crew.
가없은 윌은 데비 존스의 선원으로 일하게 됐소
Davy Jones?
데비 존스요?
Oh, please.
말도 안돼
The captain of the Flying Dutchman?
플라잉 더치맨의 선장?
- You look awful. What are you doing here? - You hired me.
-그꼴로여긴원일이야? -네가채용했잖아
I can't help it if your standards are lax.
네 수준을 알만해
- You smell funny. - Jack!
-년몸에서 냄새나 -잭!
All l want is to find Will.
월을 찾아야 돼요
Are you certain? Is that what you really want most?
진심이요? 원하는 게 정말 그거야?
Of course.
물론이죠
Because I would think you'd want to find a way to save Will most.
그럼 월을 구할 방법을 찾아야겠네
- And you'd have a way of doing that? - Well. a
- 그 방법을 알아요? -그러니까.…
- there is a chest. - Oh, dear. a
-어떤함이하나있소 -맘소사
A chest of unknown size and origin.
크기도 유래도 몰라
What contains the still-beating heart of Davy Jones.
그 함엔 데비 존스의 심장이 들었소
And whoever possesses that chest
그 함을 갖는 자는
possesses the leverage to command Jones to do whatever it is he or she wants. a
데비 존스에게 뭐든 요구할 수 있어
including saving brave William from his grim fate.
월을 그 운명에서 구해낼수도 있지
You don't actually believe him, do you?
이 얘길 정말 믿는 거요?
How would we find it?
어떻게 찾죠?
With this.
이걸로!
My compass is unique.
내 나침반은 특이한 거야
"Unique" here having the meaning of "broken."
그건 고장 났단 뜻이요
True enough, this compass does not point north.
맞아, 이 나침반은 북쪽을 안 가리켜
Where cles it point?
그럼 뭘 가리키죠?
It points to the thing you want most in this world.
나침반 주인이 가장 원하는 거
Jack.
재 ㄱ
- Are you telling the truth? - Every word, love.
-사실이에요? -물론이지
And what you want most in this world
당신이 가장 원하는 건
is to find the chest of Davy Jones, is it not?
데비 존스의 함을 찾는 거야 그렇지?
- To save Will. - By finding the chest of Davy Jones.
-월을 찾기 위해서예요 -그러려면 함을 찾아야지
- Mr. Gibbs! - Cap'n.
-김스! -네!
- We have our heading. - Finally!
-항로정했다 - 잘됐네요!
Cast off those lines. Weigh anchor and crowd that canvas!
로프 풀고 올리고 들을 모두 펴라!
Miss Swann.
스완 양
Welcome to the crew. a former commodore.
내 부하된 걸 축하해, 제독 나으리!
There's something to knowing the exact shape of the world and one’s place in it.
세상 물정 모르면 사는 게 피곤하죠 안 그래요?
l assure you, these are not necessary.
이런 거 필요 없다니까!
I thought you'd be interested in the whereabouts of your daughter.
따님 행방을 알고 싶지 않으시오?
- You have news of her? - Most recently seen on Tortuga,
- 소식 들었나? -월마전토투가에서
and then left in the company of a known pirate, Jack Sparrow,
어디론가 떠났다더군요 잭 스패로우의
and other fugitives from justice.
범법자 일당들과 함께 말이요
"Justice"? Hardly.
범법자?남말하네
Including the previous owner of this sword, I believe.
이 칼의 예전 주인도 동행했다더군
Our ships are in pursuit. Justice will be dispensed by cannonade and cutlass,
추적 중이요 모든 화력과 무기를 총동원해서
and all manner of remorseless pieces of metal.
정의의 심판을 내릴 거요
I find it distasteful to even contemplate the horror facing all those on board.
그들이 겪을 끔찍한 공포가 상상만해도 오싸군
What clo you want from me?
내게 뭘 원하나?
Your authority as governor, your influence in London,
총독으로서의 권한과 영향력
and your loyalty to the East India Trading Company.
동인도 회사에 대한 충성심!
To you, you mean.
자네에 대한 충성심이겠지
Shall l remove these shackles?
족쇄 풀어드릴까?
Do what you can for my daughter.
내 딸을 구해만 주게
So you see, Mercer, every man has a price he will willingly accept.
봤나, 머서? 고결한 척 하는 자도
Even for what he hoped never to sell.
약점을 건드리면 무너지지
I wager ten years.
이번 때에 10년 걸지
I'll match ten years.
10년에 콜!
Agreed.
나도 콜!
Wondering how it's played?
알고 구경하냐?
- Lunderstand. - Liar!
-대충이요 -사기꾼!
It's a game of deception. But your bet includes all the dice, not just your own.
상대 패도 맞춰야 되는 속고 속이는 게임이죠
- What are they wagering? - The only thing we have.
-뭘거는거죠? -걸게뭐있겠니?
Years of service.
복역햇수지
- So any crew member can be challenged? - Aye. Anyone.
-누구에게나 도전할 수 있나요? -그래
I challenge Davy Jones.
데비 존스와 붙겠소!
l accept, mate.
도전 수락하지
- The stakes? - My soul. An eternity of servitude.
-뭘 걸겠나? -내 영혼!영원히복역하는것
No!
안돼!
Against?
내겐 뭘 원해?
I want this.
이걸 주시오
- How clo you know of the key? - That's not part of the game, is it?
-열쇠에대해어떻게아나? -그건 게임과 상관없잖소
You can still walk away.
싫으면 관두든가
- What's this? - I'min. Matching his wager.
- 년 뭐야? - 나도 같은 걸 걸겠소
No! Don't do this.
안돼요!이러지 마세요
The die is cast.
주사위는 던져졌어
I bid three twos.
2끗세개
It's your bid, Captain.
당신 차례요
Four fours.
4긋네개
Four fives.
5끗네개
Six threes.
3끗 여섯 개
Seven fives.
5긋일곱개
Eight fives.
5긋 여덜 개
Welcome to the crew. lad. a
영원히 복역할각오나해
Twelve fives.
5긋 12개!
Call me a liar, or up the bid.
안 믿기면 받지 말든가
And be called a liar myself for my trouble?
거짓말이면 가만 안두겠다!
Bootstrap Bill, you're a liar and you will spend an eternity on this ship.
부스트랩, 년 날 속였다 영원히 복역해!
Master Turner. a feel free to go ashore
월 터너, 년 상륙을 허가한다
the very next time we make port!
다음 항구에 도착하면 내려!
Fool. Why did you do that?
바보 같이 왜 그랬어요?
I couldn't let you lose.
네가 질까 봐
It was never about winning or losing.
이기고 지는 건 중요치 않아요
The key.
열쇠!
You just wanted to know where it was.
열쇠 때문에 온 거였지?
Captain says I'm to relieve you.
선장이 날더러 교대하래
Captain's orders.
선장명령이야
Here. Take this. too. a
자, 이것도 가져가
Now, get yourself to land, and stay there.
이젠 육지를 떠나지 마
It was always in my blood to die at sea.
난 바다에서 죽을 운명이야
It was not a fate l ever wanted for you.
하지만년안돼
It's not a fate you had to choose for yourself, either.
왜 그런 운명을 택한 거죠?
Aye. I could say I did what I had to, when I left you to go pirating.
내가해적이 된건 얼 수 없는 일이었다
But it would taste a lie to say it wasn't what I wanted.
허나억지로선택한건아냐
You owe me nothing, Will.
년 내게 빚진 거 없어
Now go.
어서 가
They'll know you helped me.
도와주신 게 들통 날 텐데요
What more can they do to me?
더 이상뭘 겁내겠니?
I take this with a promise.
반드시 이 칼로
I'll find a way to sever Jones's hold on you,
존스의 심장을찔러
and not rest until this blade pierces his heart.
아배질 구하겠어요
I will not abandon you.
꼭 다시 올게요
I promise.
약속해요
- Beckett? - Yes, they're signed.
- 베켓? -네
Lord Cutler Beckett of the East India Trading Company.
그는 동인도 회사의 하수인이에요
Will was working for Beckett and never said a word.
월도 베켓이 보낸 거예요
Beckett wants the compass. Only one reason for that.
베켓이 나침반을 노리는 이유는 하나뿐이에요
Of course.
맞아
- He wants the chest. - Yes, he did say something about a chest.
-놈은 함을 원해 -함애길했었어요
If the company controls the chest, they controls the sea.
함만 있으면 바다를 통제하죠
- A truly discomfiting notion, love. - And bad.
- 상상만 해도 끔찍하군 -악몽이죠!
Bad for every mother's son what calls himself a pirate.
모든 해적에게 그건 최악의 악몽이에요
I think there's a bit more speed to be coaxed from these sails.
최대 항속으로 달려야겠군요
Brace the foreyard!
큰 들을 펴!
Might l enquire as to how you came by these?
어떻게 구했는지 물어도 되겠소?
- Persuasion. - Friendly?
-설득했죠 -우호적으로?
Decidedly not.
아뇨, 별로
Will strikes a deal, yet you were the one with the prize - full pardon.
월이 제안에 응하면 당신 둘은 사면되고
"Commission as a privateer on behalf of England
난 동인도 회사 소속
"and the East India Trading Company.”
민간선 선장이 된다?
As if l could be bought for such a low price.
내 몸값이 너무 싸군
- Jack, the letters, give them back. - No.
-잭,편지줘요 -싫소!
Persuade me.
날 설득해봐
You do know Will taught me how to handle a sword?
월에게 칼 쓰는 법배웠어요
As l said, persuade me.
못 들었소? 설득해보라니까
It's a curious thing.
묘한일이군
There was a time I would have wanted you to look like that while thinking about me.
난그미소 보려고 별 짓을 다했는데
- [don't know what you mean. - [ think you do.
- 무슨 뜻이죠? - 알잖소
Don't be absurd. I trust him. that's all. a
난잭을 믿을 뿐이에요
So you never wondered how your latest fiancé
과연 플라잉 더치맨에
ended up on the Flying Dutchman in the first place?
왜 월이 타게 됐을까 궁금하지 않소?
Strange to come upon a longboat so far out in open water.
보트로 어떻게 심해까지 왔나?
Just put as many leagues behind us as you can. As fast as you can.
그보다, 빨리 여길 벗어나요
And what are we running from?
뭐가 쫓아오나?
That dress. Where did you get it?
이 드레스 어디서 났죠?
It was found aboard the ship.
배에서 발견됐네
The crew thought it was a spirit bringing some omen of ill-fate.
다들 유령의 저주라고 했지
- That's foolish. - Yes. Exceedingly foolish.
-바보같이.… - 맞아요, 바보들이죠
It brought good fortune. The spirit told us, "Pull in at Tortuga,”
그 옷이 복덩이예요 우리한테 토투가로 가랬거든요
and we made a nice bit of profit there.
덕분에 돈벌었죠
Off the books, of course. a
개인 수입 좀챙겼지
l imagine some of your crew may have jumped ship there.
선원 한 명이 거기서 사라졌죠?
- Why do you ask? - Captain! A ship's been spotted.
-왜묻나? -배가한척보입니다!
- Colors? - She isn't flying any.
-깃발색은? -깃발이 없어요
- Pirates. - Or worse.
-해적이야! -그럼 다행이죠
You will watch this.
똑똑히 잘 봐뒤라
Let no joyful voice be heard!
모두 절망속에 절규하리라!
Let no man look up at the sky with hope.
하늘을 보며 울부으리라!
And let this day be cursed by we who ready to wake
이 날이 영원토록 저주로 기억되도록
the kraken.
크라켄을 불러라!
No!
안돼!
I've doomed us all.
다나때문이야
It's the Flying Dutchman!
플라잉 더치맨 호요!
Mother Carey's chickens! What happened?
젠장, 이게 뭔 일이야?
Must have hit a reef.
암초에 부덧혔나?
Free the rudder! Hard to port then hard to starboard.
좌현으로 꺼은 뒤 우현으로 틀어!
- Free the rudder! - Hard to port!
-방향타를 나! - 우현으로!
- Kraken!
크라켄이다!
Here it is! Take it!
자 여기 있다, 가져가!
Take it!
가져가라고!
The boy's not here. He must have been claimed by the sea.
놈은 없습니다 바다에 빠졌나 봐요
lam the sea.
내가 곧바다야
You need time alone with your thoughts.
혼자 슬퍼할시간을 주지
- Brig! - What of the survivors?
-영창에넣어! -생존자들은요?
There are no survivors.
한 놈도 살려두지 마
The chest is no longer safe. Chart a course to Isla Cruces.
이젠 함이 안전치 못 해 죽음의 섬으로 가자
Get me there first. a or there'll be the devil to pay.
우리가먼저 도착해야돼!
"First"?
먼저라뇨?
Who sent that thieving charlatan onto my ship?
누가 놈을 내 배에 보냈겠나?
Who told him of the key?
누가 열쇠 얘길 했겠어?
Jack Sparrow.
잭 스패로우야
My intuitive sense of the female creature informs me that you are troubled.
내뛰어난직감으로 볼때 당신은 고민이 있어
I just thought I'd be married by now.
결혼이 첩질 않네요
I'm so ready to be married.
난준비가됐는데
You know...
이봐.…
Lizzie, l am captain of a ship,
난이배의선장이야
and being captain of a ship, I could in fact perform a "marr-i-age” right here.
맘만 먹으면 당장 결혼할 수 있어 바로 이곳.…
Right on this deck.
갑판위에서
Right now.
지금 당장!
No, thank you.
사양할래요
Why not?
왜?
We are very much alike, you and I. land you. Us.
당신과 난 닮았어, 안 그래?
Except for a sense of honor and decency and a moral center.
인간성, 도덕관념 윤리 의식만뻐면요
And personal hygiene.
거기다위생관념
Trifles.
그런 건 별거 아냐
You will come over to my side. I know it.
당신도 곧 나처럼 살게 돼
- You seem very certain. - One word, love. Curiosity.
- 자신만만하군요 -왜냐?호기심 때문이지!
You long for freedom.
당신은 세상을
You long to do what you want to do because you want it.
자유롭게 살고 싶어해
To act on selfish impulse.
이기적인 본능대로
You want to see what it's like.
그런 삶을 맛보고 싶지?
One day, you won't be able to resist.
언젠간억제 못할 날이 와
Why doesn't your compass work?
왜 나침반이 고장 났는지 알아요?
My compass works fine.
내 나침반은 멀째
Because you and I are alike,
당신은 좋은 분이거든요
and there will come a moment when you have a chance to show it.
그걸 증명할 때가
- To do the right thing. - Llove those moments.
-곧을거예요 -기다려지는군
l like to wave at them as they pass by.
그날이 오면 '잘 가' 해야지
You'll have the chance to do something... something courageous.
용기를 보여줄 기회가 올 거예요
And when you do, you'll discover something.
그럼 깨닫겠죠
That you're a good man.
자신이 좋은 사람임을
All evidence to the contrary.
그 반대쪽 같은데?
I have faith in you.
난 당신 믿어요
- Want to know why? - Do tell. dearie. a
-웹지알아요? -궁금하군
Curiosity.
호기심 때문이죠
You're going to want it.
곧느끼게 돼요
A chance to be admired and gain the rewards that follow.
존경 받는 인간이 되고 싶은 강한 욕구를
You won't be able to resist.
억제하기 힘들걸요?
You're going to want to know what it tastes like.
그런 삶이 어떤 건지 맛보고 싶을 거예요
I do want to know what it tastes like.
정말 그 맛을 보고 싶군
But, seeing as you're a good man,
당신은 좋은 사람이라
l know that you'd never put me in a position that would compromise my honor.
내 명예에 흠낼 짓 못해요
I'm proud of you, Jack.
잘 참는군요
Land. ho! a
육지다!
Il want my jar of clirt.
흙 담은 병!
- You're pulling too fast. - You're pulling too slow.
-너무 빨리 지마 -네가느린거야
- We don't want the kraken to catch us. - I'm saving me strength for when it comes.
-크라켄밥되고싶어? -힘 아겼다놈오면 튀어야지!
And I don't think it's "kracken” anyways. l always heard it said "krayken.”
그리고 정확한 발음은 크레이켄이라고!
With a long a?
^를 장모음으로?
No, no. no. no, no. no. no. "Krocken” ce is how it's pronounced in Scandinavian,
아니, 그게 아냐 스칸디나비아에선 다들
and "kracken” is closer to that.
크라켄으로 발음해
We ain't Scandinavians. are we? a "Krayken.”
우리가 스칸디나비아 인이냐? 크레이켄이야!
It's a mythological creature. I can calls it what I wants.
신화 속 괴물인데 아무렴 어때?
Guard the boat. Mind the tide.
배안떠내려가게 잘 지키고
Don't touch my dirt.
내 흙에 손대지 마
This doesn't work. And it certainly doesn't show you what you want most.
고장이에요 원하는 걸 안 가리켜요!
Yes, it does. You're sitting on it.
잘 가리키는데? 그 자리야
- Beg pardon? - Move.
-뭐라고요? -비켜
- "Guard the boat!” "Mind the tide!” - [could join the circus.
-배나잘지키라고? -나광대 될까?
Mind if l shine your shoes, sir?
우리가 종이야?
They're here. And I cannot step foot on land again for near of a decade.
왔다, 난땅못 밝아 너희가 가
You'll trust us to act in your stead?
저휠 믿으십니까?
I'll trust you to know what awaits you should you fail!
그래, 배신의 대가를 알 테니까!
- Down, then! a - Down!
-내려가자! -내려가!
It's real.
진짜심장이에요
You actually were telling the truth.
거짓말이 아니었군
I do that quite a lot, yet people are always surprised.
나정직해 다들 못 믿어 문제지
With good reason!
그럴 만하지!
Will!
월!
You're all right! Thank God! I came to find you!
무사했군요! 당신을 찾으러 왔어요
How did you get here?
어떻게 왔나?
Sea turtles. mate. a A pair of them, strapped to my feet.
바다거북두 마리를 발에 칭칭 묶고!
Not so easy, is it?
그거 힘들지?
- But l do owe you thanks, Jack. - You do?
-어든 고마워요 -뭐가?
After you tricked me onto that ship to square your debt with Jones...
날속여서 데비 존스 배에 태운 거
- What?
-뭐라고요? -뭐?
..l was reunited with my father.
그 덕에 아버질 만났어요
Well, you're welcome, then.
고맘다니 고맘군
Everything you said to me, every word was a lie!
나한테 말한 게 전부 다거짓이었군요!
Pretty much.
대부분은
Time and ticle, love. a
상황이 그랬거든
Oi! What are you doing?
이봐, 뭐 하는 거야?
I'm going to kill Jones.
존스를 죽일 거요
Can't let you do that, William.
존스가 죽으면
‘Cause if Jones is dead. who's to call a his terrible beastie off the hunt. eh?
크라켄이 날 못 쫓게 명령 내릴 자가 없어져
Now, if you please.
자, 이제 주시지
The key.
열쇠!
l keep the promises I make, Jack.
아너질 구해야 돼
l intend to free my father. l hope you're here to see it.
방해하면 당신을 죽일 수 밖에
I can't let you do that either. So sorry.
나도 그건 허락 못 해 미안하네
I knew you'd warm up to me eventually.
내편될줄알았어
Lord Beckett desires the content of that chest.
베켓 경이 그 함에 든 걸 원해
I deliver it, l get my life back.
갖다 주면 내 지위는 복원돼
The dark sicle of ambition.
흑심이 있으셨군
I prefer to see it as the promise of redemption.
인생을 되찾으려는 노력이지
Stop it!
그만해요!
Will!
월!
- Guard the chest! - No!
-함을 지켜요! -안돼요!
This is barbaric! This is no way for grown men to...
이건 야만적인 짓이에요! 다큰 어른들이 유치하게.…
Fine! Let's just haul out our swords and start banging away at each other.
네, 좋아요! 그럼 칼태리고맨손으로 싸워요!
That will solve everything! I've had it!
주먹으로 하라고요! 나도 지긋지긋해!
I've had it with wobbly-legged, rum-soaked pirates!
럼주에찌든 이 야만인 해적들아!
- How'd this go all screwy? - Well. each wants the chest for hisself. a
-왜셋이저렇게됐지? -서로 함을 차지하려는 거지
Mr. Norrington, I think, is trying to regain a bit of honor,
노링턴은 명예회복을 위해서
old Jack's looking to trade it, save his own skin. a
잭은 자기가 살기 위해서
then Turner, there, I think he's trying to settle some unresolved business
그리고월 터너는아버지와의
‘twixt him and his twice-cursed pirate father.
묵은 갈등을 풀기 위해서
- Sad. - This is madness!
-슬픈일이군 -미친짓관뒤요!
That chest must be worth more than a shiny penny.
저 함에 꽤 중요한 게 들었나 봐
Terrible temptation.
유혹적인 그 무엇!
If we was any kind of decent, we'd remove temptation from their path.
유혹으로부터 저들을 구해주는 게 도리 아닐까?
Enough!
그만해요!
The heat!
아, 어지러워!
Bugger!
젠장!
By your leave, Mr. Turner.
먼저 실례할게, 터너
By your leave, Mr. Norrington.
먼저 실례할게, 노링턴
Do excuse me while I kill the man who ruined my life.
내 인생 작살낸 놈 손 좀 봐줘도 되겠지?
- Be my guest. - Let us examine that claim for a moment.
-월마든지 -말은 바로 해, 전직 제독 나으리
Who was it, that at the very moment you had a notorious pirate safely behind bars,
네가 악명 높은 해적을 감옥에 가뒷을 때
saw fit to free said pirate and take your dearly beloved all to hisself?
그 해적을 탈출시키고 약혼녀를 가론 게 누군데?
So whose fault is it, really,
누구 때문에 네가
that you've ended up a rum-pot deckhand what takes orders from pirates?
해적선의 주정뱅이 잡역부가 됐느냐 그거지
Enough!
그만해!
Unfortunately, Mr. Turner, he's right!
불행히도 저 놈 말이 맞아!
Still rooting for you, mate.
난 자네 편이야, 노링턴!
We got it! We got it! We got it!
이제 우리 거야!
Hello, poppet.
안녕, 예쁜이?
Come on. run! a
야, 빨리 뛰어!
- Sword! - Sword! Sword!
-칼!
Sword!
칼!
Follow my voice.
내 목소릴 따라와!
To the left... no, turn around. a
왼쪽, 왼쪽!
Go to the right.
오른쪽으로!
No, that's a tree. a
아냐, 거긴 나무잖아!
Shut it.
조용히 해!
dar of dirt!
흙 담은 병!
Right.
좋아!
We've got it!
이건 우리 거야!
Come on. Turner! a
어서 덤벼!
Leave him lie! Unless you plan on using him to hit something with.
냄 뒤! 그녀석한테신경쓸때아냐
- We're not getting out of this. - Not with the chest.
-다틀렸어요 -함만 없으면 돼
Into the boat.
배에 타요!
- You're mad! - Don't wait for me.
-미쳤군요 -기다리지 마요!
- lsay we respect his final wish. - Aye!
-죽으려고 용쓰는데 뒤 -념!
Your bravery is wasted.
년 용기를 낭비했어
I shall pry the chest away from your cold, dead hands.
이제 네 시신에서 함을 빼낼 일만 남았군
Here you go!
가져!
Pirates!
해적 놈!
- What happened to the chest? - Norrington took it to draw them off.
-함어디있소? -노링턴이 놈들 유인한다고.…
- You're pulling too hare! - You ain't pulling hard enough!
-너무 빨리 졌잖아! -네가느려!
- Where's the commodore? - Fell behind.
-제독은요? -뒤쳐졌어
My prayers be with him.
명복을 빌어야겠군
Best not wallow in our grief.
좋게 생각합시다
The bright side is you're back, and made it off free and clear.
선장도 돌아오셨고 모든 게 해결됐잖아요!
Lord on high, deliver us.
신이여, 도와주소서
I'll handle this, mate. a
내가 해결하지
Oi. fishface!
문어 대마왕!
Lose something? Eh? Scungilli!
찾는 거 있어? 이거 아냐?
Got it!
안깨졌어!
Come to negotiate, eh, have you, you slimy git?
협상하러 왔나?
Look what I got.
내가 뭘 갖고 있게?
! got a jar of dirt. {got a jar of dirt
혹즐승은 응족4
And guess what's inside it?
유가 을유을요2
Enough!
공격해!
- Hard to starboard. - Hard to starboard!
- 우현으로 급선회 - 우현으로 급선회!
Brace up the foreyard!
로프 단단히 매!
Hard to starboard!
우현으로 선회해!
Send his beloved Pear! back to the depths.
블랙펼을 바다 밑에 수장시켜!
She's on us! She's on us!
뒤에 온다! 바로 뒤에 있어!
- Let them taste the triple guns. - Aye, Captain.
-회전대포의 맛을 보여줘 -네, 선장님!
Make fast!
단단히 동여매!
Go on, me darling! Show us what you've got!
블랙펄, 제발 살려다오
Come on, girl!
더힘내!
- She's falling behind! - Aye. We've got her!
-뒤쳐져요! - 따돌렸어요!
- We're the faster? - Against the wind, the Dutchman beats us.
-우리가빠른가? - 맞바람엔 느려도
- But with the wind... - We rob her advantage.
-바람탈땐 다르죠 -우리가빠르다?
Aye.
네!
We're out of range!
사라져갑니다!
Break off pursuit, run her light and douse canvas!
추적 중지해! 불 풀고 들 내려!
We're giving up. sir?
포기할 겁니까?
They're giving up!
안 따라온다!
My father is on that ship.
아내지가저배에탓어요
We can take her. We should turn and fight.
우리 속도가빠르면 싸워보자고요
Why fight when you can negotiate? All one needs is the proper leverage.
협상할 수 있는데 왜 싸워? 칼자루를 건 우리 쪽이 야
Where is it? Where is the thump-thump?
어디 있어? 발이 달려 도망갔나?
We must have hit a reef!
암초가 있습니다!
No. It's not a reef! Get away from the rail!
맘소사, 암초가 아냐! 물러서요!
- What is it? - The kraken.
-뭔데요? -크라켄이요
- To arms! - Load guns! Defend the mast!
-무장해! -마스트쪽을 방어해!
Itll attack the starboard. Run out the cannons and hold for my signal!
우현 쪽을 조심해! 대포 발사 준비하고!
Easy, boys!
모두 침착해!
Will?
월?
Steady! Steady.
기다려, 조금만 더
- Will! - Hold. Hold.
-월! -조금만더
I think we've held fire long enough.
이제 그만 발포 명령해요!
- Will! - Fire!
-월! -발사!
- It ll be back. We have to get off the ship. - There's no boats.
- 다시 올 거요, 탈출해야 돼 -보트가없어요
Pull the grates. Get all the gunpowder onto the net in the cargo hold!
수하물 칸 열고 화약을 그물에 담아!
- Whatever you do, don't miss. - As soon as you're clear.
-겨냥잘해요 -필요할때쏟게요
We are short-stocked on gunpowder! Six barrels!
화약이 모자랍니다! 6통 남았어요!
Hurry up!
빨리!
- There's only six kegs of powder! - Then load the rum.
-6통 밖에 없답니다! - 그럼 럼주를 실어!
Aye. the rum too!
럼주도 그물에 실어!
Step to!
서둘러요!
You coward.
비겁한 인간
Not good.
불길하군
- Haul away! - Heave!
-꼴어올려! - 올려!
- Heave like you're being paid for it! - Put your backs into it!
-젖먹던힘을 다해서! -있는힘껏밀어!
- L got you! I got you! - Don't let me go!
-염려마,곧뻐줄게! -놓지 마요!
- lL won't let you go! - Shoot me!
-안뇌! -날 싸요!
- Clear? - Higher! Higher!
-비켜요! -더 높이 올려!
Here! Come on!
덤벼!
Come and get me. I'm over here!
와서 잡아먹어봐!
Come on!
어서!
Shoot! Elizabeth, shoot! a
싸요, 엘리자베스!
Did we kill it?
죽었어요?
No. We just made it angry.
아니, 성질만 더 돋어
We're not out of this yet. Captain, orders!
대비해야돼 선장, 명령 내려줘요!
Abandon ship. Into the longboat.
배는 버리고 보트에 타!
Jack. The Pear!.
선장! 블랙펄을 버려요?
She's only a ship, mate.
그냥배일뿐이야
He's right. We have to head for land.
육지로 가야돼요
- It's a lot of open water. - It's a lot of water.
-육지는 까마득해요 -맞아요
We have to try. We can get away as it takes down the Peari.
시도는 해봐야지 가라앉을 동안 탈출해야 돼
Abandon ship.
배를내려
Abandon ship or abandon hope.
배를내려야살수있다!
Thank you, Jack.
고마워요, 잭
We're not free yet, love.
안심하긴 이르지
You came back.
돌아온 거 말이에요
l always knew you were a good man.
좋은 분인 거 알고 있었어요
Prepare to cast off. There's no time to lose.
어서 출발 준비해! 뭘 꾸물대?
Come on, Will. Step to!
빨리 내려가요, 월!
It's after you, not the ship.
놈이 쫓는 건 당신이지
It's not us.
우리가 아니에요
This is the only way, don't you see?
방법은 이것뿐이에요
I'm not sorry.
미안하지 않아요
Pirate.
해적 감이야
Where's Jack?
잭은?
He elected to stay behind to give us a chance.
우릴 살리려고 남았어요
Go!
가요!
Bugger. Bugger. bugger.
제발 좀.…
Come on!
제발!
Just got it. Come on.
됐어, 조금만 더
Not so bad.
냄새 안심하네
Hello, beastie. a
안녕, 크라켄
Jack Sparrow, our debt is settled.
잭 스패로우, 이제 빚을 갖았군
The captain goes down with his ship.
저렇게 사라지다니
Turns out not even Jack Sparrow can best the devil.
잭도 크라켄에겐 못 당하는군
Open the chest.
함을 열어
Open the chest. I need to see it!
확인해 봐야겠다!
Damn you, Jack Sparrow!
이 망할 놈, 잭 스패로우!
The last of our ships is returned.
배들이 다 돌아왔습니다
Is there any news on the chest?
함에 관한 소식은?
None. But one of the ships did pick up a man adirift at sea.
표류자한 명을 건져 올렸는데
He had these.
이걸 갖고 있었답니다
I took the liberty of filling in my name.
그 안에 내 이름을 써넣었소
If you intend to claim these, then you must have something to trade.
그럼 교환할 걸 제시해야지
Do you have the compass?
나침반 가져왔나?
Better.
더 좋은 거
The heart of Davy Jones.
데비 존스의 심장이요
Against the cold
추위가 가실 거야
and the sorrow.
슬픔도.…
It's a shame.
유감이군
I know you're thinking that with the Pear!
블랙펄이 있으면
you could have captured the devil and set free your father's soul.
존스를 잡아 부친을 구했을 텐데
Doesn't matter now.
이젠 상관없소
The Pear! is gone,
배는 사라졌소
along with its captain.
선장과함께
Aye.
그래요
And already the world seems a bit less bright.
이제 세상이 빚을 잃었소
He fooled us all right till the end,
우릴 속이고 남다니!
but I guess that honest streak finally won out.
고결한 인격이 결국 드러난 거요
To Jack Sparrow.
잭 스패로우를 위하여!
- Never another like Captain Jack. - He was a gentleman of fortune, he was.
-멋진선장이었는데 -해적계의 신사였어!
He was a good man.
좋은 분이었죠
If there was anything could be done to bring him back...
그를 되살릴 방법만 있다면.…
- Elizabeth. - Would you clo it?
-엘리자베스 - 해볼 거야?
What would you...
뭐든 할 수 있어?
What would any of you be willing to do, hm?
무슨 짓이든 할 수 있어?
Would you sail to the ends of the Earth and beyond
바다 끝까지라도 가서
to fetch back witty Jack and him precious Pear!?
잭과 블랙펄을 구해올 마음이 있어?
Aye.
있소!
Yes.
있어요
All right.
좋아
But if you go and brave the weird and haunted shores at world’s end. a
하지만 유령이 나오는 바다 끝세상으로 가려면
then you will need a captain who knows those waters.
그곳을 잘 아는 선장이 필요해
So tell me. a what's become of my ship?
말해봐 내 배가 어떻게 됐다고?